hey guys I got a good video for you
today I'm here with Coach Ben Bruno and
he's here to show you guys his top four
favorite landmine exercises and first
off we've got the single leg
RDL I'm going to show you guys two
different ways to do landmine single leg
rdls the reason I like the land mine is
the fixed bar position creates a little
bit of artificial stability to help with
balance so you're not worrying so much
about being tippy and can do the
movement a little cleaner and focus more
on the on strengthening the posterior
tank so two ways to do them before we go
over this I want to say that neither way
is better nor worse they're just
different so probably try both after
watching this video and see which one
you like better um I will go into it a
little more detail when I go over the
two variations but certain people do
better with one variation or the other
depending on their problems first one is
standing perpendicular to the landline
unit so what you're going to do is stand
so that the tip of the bar is right in
line with the inside leg grab the bar
right at the end with your thumb over
the bar here and then put this arm out
and make a fist it it seems a little bit
count uh counterintuitive but this
having this arm Lim makes this the whole
body Lim so it's actually a little bit
harder to balance
on the clip side if you make a fist here
creates tension all the way through and
there's a little bit more stability so
you're going to start here all you're
going to do go
down come back up down come back up now
I want to go over a couple common issues
that I see one is trying to grip the bar
choking up when you do that it's going
to be harder to hold the bar because
you're holding this slck part and it's
also going to hit you in the leg as you
come down so instead you want to grab
just at the edge right in line with the
leg the other setup problem that you'll
see is setting up with the bar outside
the body this happens because people
want to pick up the bar to start outside
their body but the problem with that is
that the bar travels on an ark so when
it comes out it's too far away from your
body so start right in line come up arm
to the side
and then HPS all the way through another
issue that you'll see is people not
coming all the way through and and kind
of hanging out like this that doesn't
get the glutes to get the glutes you
want to go all the way through and tap
your leg with the bar that means you
came all the way through St all the way
up last problem I want to go over with
this variation is what I call the peen
dog on the back leg that's where instead
of doing what I was doing before they
open up that back foot and come down
like that I don't actually care about
the back foot but I do care that the
pelvis is relatively straight so this is
usually indicative that one hip is
Raising so to fix that tell people to
get that toe square and what I'll
actually do is instruct them to point in
slightly so that as they go back it kind
of straightens out and you get a little
more so what that'll look like is
instead of starting neutral and opening
up you'll start slightly closed and
it'll straighten
out so that is how I'd like you to set
up for the perpendicular version the
other way would be facing the landmar
now here the ark is going to be used to
your advantage in a different way in the
perpendicular version you're actually
the arc is making the bar come across
your body which help activates helps to
activate this glute and help with
balance
here set up like this arm out to the
side the bar is actually if you think
it's marking slightly back so for people
that tend to reach with kettal bells or
dumbbells this makes it impossible to do
that so here you're going to set up the
bar straight in line with the body again
just at the edge of the bar flat back
picking it up you'll go here straight
back and forward and all the way through
again watching to do that PE dog of this
if you if you notice when I go to do
that I'm
tipping when I don't it's a lot more
stable so here make sure that the bar is
right in line with the leg some people
want to set up with the bar outside the
leg and that makes it a little bit
awkward come right here
again the bar fills that Gap through the
Le is comes through leg touches to
ensure the hip comes all the way through
then flat back putting it down so those
are the two ways to do it try both and
see which way you like better